In a world where there's so much
financial repression, it's really
important that all of us in our
generation open our eyes widely and look
for the things that are 6040 actually
isn't working. We have to start with the
question of why is traditional 6040
breaking apart. The global financial
crisis happened and everything that I
ever learned was thrown out the window
and we would continue to then have
decades of financial repression in ways
that there was no textbooks. So the
radical portfolio was actually something
that I personally experienced in my
years to reimagine what a real portfolio
allocation theory should look like.
After the global financial crisis, most
of the price action that is arising out
of securities and assets is due to
government intervention and crossber
flows. So everyone these days seems to
know the price of everything but knows
the value of nothing. I consider time to
be one of the component of of energy
that can be created that can be turned
into value. Young people have already
intuited. Most of the financial economy
is a little bit rigged. Zero day x-ray
options are more than 50% of the trading
volume of your S&P 500 and NASDAQ listed
options. These are literally lotto
tickets. And the fact that this
hyperfinancialization is happening with
regulators consent shows you it's
becoming so casino. And I think when
young people see that happening, their
reaction is totally natural to say, "I'm
not going to play that game." When you
bet on Bitcoin, you're not always
betting on the price of Bitcoin going
up. Sometimes you're betting on the
price of fiat going down.
>> Other um companies trying to copy
strategy strategy with Salana or with
Ethereum.
>> And I'll tell you why. Any lessons
you've learned from Morgan Stanley's
experience? The number one lesson
[Music]
Jeff Park joins us today. He is the head
of Alpha Strategies and portfolio
manager at Bitwise Asset Management.
We'll be talking about his views on the
markets relating to cryptos and Bitcoin.
Welcome to the show, Jeff. Good to see
you. My name is David
>> Bonnie. We had your colleague uh Matt on
the show, Matt Hooan, and um he was
great. People should check out that
interview. We had him on New York, links
down below. But uh we like to get your
outlook on uh on Bitcoin and cryptos.
>> He's super popular on Twitter and a lot
of people follow him. And one of the
most popular post was the radical
portfolio.
What is a radical portfolio?
>> That's a great question. Um so I grew up
learning about traditional economics and
finance that most of my life and when I
started my career it was 2008 so you can
imagine at the very beginning two months
into my job the global financial crisis
happened and everything that I ever
learned was thrown out the window and we
would continue to then have decades of
financial repression in ways that there
was no textbooks. So the radical
portfolio was actually something that I
personally experienced in my years to
reimagine what a real portfolio
allocation theory should look like for
the future generation. We're all taught
about 60/40 pretty early on. 60 fixed
income, 40 equities for growth. And that
balanced portfolio should give you a
diversified upside capture in a
riskadjusted manner. And what I think
we're realizing is 6040 actually isn't
working because bonds and equities are
more correlated in fact now than people
have ever expected them to be. So the
radical portfolio is a whole new way to
reimagine what should be a diversified
portfolio 60% of something and 40% of
something else and how do we
reparameterize those risk factors and
that's the essential genesis of my
radical portfolio theory.
>> So how do you allocate what is the new
theory then? Yeah. So we have to start
with the question of why is traditional
60/40 breaking apart. And when you uh
ask that question what you find is that
after the global financial crisis most
of the price action that is arising out
of securities and assets is due to
government intervention and crossber
flows. So because of the great fiscal
expenditures that the entire global
monetary order system has been embarking
on, the distortion that is coming from
the concept of GDP has changed
massively. So when GDP includes things
like government expenditure as a way to
imagine growth, you can kind of imagine
is government spending actually growth
in the way that we want to capture it.
So bonds are starting to look like risk
assets in ways that people used to think
bonds were riskoff assets. So once that
awakening happens the question is 6040
is actually 100 of something and what is
that 100 and the argument that I would
make is that it is 100% of compliance
assets. These are assets that we are
trading in the world of abundance where
there's a lot of ways to access it
through brokerages and there's
financialization there's leverage and
this is essentially the underpinning of
the global carry system as we know it.
So what's the ultimate hedge for that?
what is the 40% that can hedge the 100%
of compliance and that I call the
resistance assets. So now we're talking
about assets that are actually difficult
to access. These are not things you can
buy on stock markets. These are actually
somewhat nonfgeible in nature in where
they actually cannot be levered. They're
one of a kind. So the 40% has to be
outside the system in the global carry
system as we know it. And that's what
gives it a defining unique value. So
perfect example of that is gold. And
when I say gold, I don't mean GLD, the
ETF. I mean physical gold bars, right?
Because that represents the ability to
be censorship resistant in ways that you
remove yourself from the financials
ecosystem. Bitcoin also represents a way
to express a view on having a resistance
asset. And so I list a variety of
different alternative things that can
fit the profile of what that should be.
These things can include
uh you know high-end art, one-of-a-kind
artworks that really are irreplaceable
and truly truly valuable that cannot be
replicated and those things retain value
because the scarcity value is actually
really important. So the 100% compliance
of bonds and equities, the reason why
they're not that uh valuable is because
they're printed all the time. So other
categories include things like
collectibles, um, Pokemon cards in ways,
even though it's a joke, do retain
values in ways for certain people. And
that category might evolve into luxury
handbags like the Birkens of the world
where those things are equally valuable
because of the scarcity and hold value
actually much better than uh, some other
traditional assets would.
>> It sounds like an alternative
investments portfolio. Is that one way
to look at it?
>> Exactly. But it's alternatives in a way
that isn't fitting nicely into the
the language that we know how to speak
of. No one talks about buying Pokemon
cards or handbags or artwork or these
scarce assets as a way to diversify your
portfolio because it's not tradable,
right? These are not like ETFs that you
can buy where you have an index exposure
to luxury goods or you can't buy biotech
IP rights or legal IP rights in easily
accessible ways. These are essentially
scarce things and scarcity is valuable
and I think that's the main point that
I'm trying to drive which is in a world
where there's so much financial
repression it's really important that
all of us in our generation open our
eyes widely and look for the things that
are not manufactured abundance and
that's why Bitcoin I think is especially
important today for everyone.
>> What is the most valuable Pokemon card
then today?
>> I think if I'm not mistaken
>> he has an answer for us. I do. Listen
up.
>> I do happen to be a little bit of an
expert in this market.
I believe there is a Japanese Pikachu
card
>> uh released for his birthday
>> and it's Pikachu's birthday card and
there's very very very few of these that
are out there.
>> Okay.
>> And they're very valuable.
>> All right.
>> Especially if it's in good condition.
>> What is very valuable?
>> I believe it's um close to uh million
dollars.
Fore
speak.
Hey, I'm about to interview one of the
biggest names in crypto. That's
exciting.
Elsa,
speech analyzer.
Fore
premium.
I know this is like facitious and funny,
but like there is a methodology to
looking for value, right? You could the
same methodology that you used to apply
to that Pokemon card can be applied to
an alt for example or a piece of art,
right? Walk us through the thought
process here. Yeah, the essential
>> principles of scarcity, principles of um
collectibility, the principles of
desiraability.
>> Yeah, absolutely. The main principle is
that it has to be scarce, hard assets in
ways that it cannot be manufactured. Um,
it's even better if it can actually
deteriorate over time, so they disappear
and the supply decreases. For example,
the reason the Pikachu Pokemon card is
valuable isn't because they were so many
of them. It's because many of them also
disappeared throughout the life of its
course or the conditions worsened. So
those things increase value. It's also
why fine wine is a huge category that
people buy as a way to store value
because wine also deteriorates over
time. So if you protect it and perfect
it, the value is exponentially higher.
>> And so scarcity is the most important
thing. I would also argue that these
assets have some elements of
nonfgeibility where you can't apply
leverage very easily and because so much
of the value driven from equities and
fixed income come from the credit
system. This is a low volatility kind of
situation when it comes to the ability
to apply leverage mostly because the
asset is high volatility and that is
actually the inherent quality we're
looking for. We want assets that are
highly volatile because it has inherent
endogenous energy for performance and it
isn't being manufactured to be volatile
for the sake of it when the asset itself
is not very volatile which is the entire
birthing of the kind of financial system
as we know it.
>> Do you go to do you go to Bitwise and
say we want 40% in Pokemon cards?
>> I is is there like a model you use to
allocate how many how much of your to
your This is my personal allocation
strategy. I collect a lot of random art.
You know, I'm a big fan of Daniel
Arsham, for example, and Daniel Arsham
has a following, right? Which is that he
combines some kind of street culture
with high-end art as well. He's in, you
know, meaningful galleries. And um the
Murakami of the world is a category and
so those things are useful in your
portfolio diversification. I should
mention the third piece of what makes
these valuable is it has to be somewhat
censorship resistant. So this goes back
to the notion of opting out of the
system where bonds and equities you're
in a system where you're trading these
to brokerages. You're generally not the
custodial holders of these securities
instruments anyway. Even if you own
Microsoft stock, it's generally not in
your name. It's in actually the
custodian's name on behalf of your name.
>> So true ownership is really important.
This is why uh gold versus GLD ETF is
important and it's because if you really
believe there's diversification away
from the compliance world as we know it
then these are the assets that's going
to retain more value because the virtue
of not being in the system where it's
tangibly yours is the key feature of
what makes it valuable.
>> I want to ask you so what is value? What
creates value? Yesterday, Peter Schiff
was sitting there. He said, "You
Bitcoiners are just trading nothing.
You're buying nothing." What how would
you respond to that?
>> Yeah. I would respond with a famous
adage. I did not coin this, but one that
I love, which is that everyone these
days seems to know the price of
everything, but knows the value of
nothing, which is that we live in a
world of so much information, right? We
see tick by tick of all these trading
activities and high frequency trading
opportunities where it seems to intimate
a sense of value because of the
transactional dynamic. But the reality
is those things are just moments in
times of transactional dynamics where it
doesn't truly mean that's its terminal
value forever. And so things that are
actually truly valuable sometimes do not
trade. Sometimes the most valuable
things actually are meant to be held for
a long time. So think about how
billionaires these days invest in things
like sports clubs and franchises. These
things don't trade. They're actually,
you know, once in a lifetime
generational transaction for which value
is created and transferred. Um, so I
actually think people often confuse
value being related to price. But the
difference is price is the reflection of
someone's intention to pay for something
whereas the value is actually something
that inherently is worth which you don't
actually always know until there's a
time to experience it.
>> Does it have to be a consensus like the
majority of population recognize that
this thing cost $2,000
>> or
>> everyone could be wrong.
>> Yeah, that's the thing. It's um value is
ultimately dependent at some level on
your personal preference and that's why
older people love gold and young people
love bitcoin and at some level these are
personal choices but the other reason
why I'm so optimistic about uh bitcoin
and generally these resistance assets is
because I think young people have
already intuited most of the financial
economy is a little bit rigged. So they
have this sense of the stock market
generally not being healthy. And I
actually do think that in some ways our
system has failed in promoting that
narrative of a healthy robust market of
fair practice. Think about the trends of
for example nowadays zero day expir
options are more than 50% of the trading
volume of your S&P 500 and NASDAQ listed
options. Zero day expir options, right?
These are literally lotto tickets. And
the fact that this hyperfinancialization
is happening with regulators consent
shows you it's becoming so casino. And I
think when young people see that
happening, their reaction is totally
natural to say, I'm not going to play
that game cuz I don't really know it,
but I'm just going to buy the things I
know and I like because at least that is
valuable to me. And other young people
say that is valuable to me as well. And
I think actually that's what ultimately
creates value as we come to appreciate
it.
>> Okay. Uh, let's get your macro outlook
on some of these assets that you brought
up. So, you brought up gold. Let's
compare gold to Bitcoin. I read this the
other day, not yet the other day.
Yesterday, it came out yesterday. Um, as
of the date of the recording, May 29th,
Goldman Sachs analyst predicts 4,000
gold, calling it a better hedge than
Bitcoin. 4,000 by mid 2026. This is his
quote from an analyst here. Supply is
very limited. The vast majority of
available gold supply has already been
mined. And Bitcoin supply by design is
also limited. I think this limited
supply gives some confidence to
investors who are worried about runaway
inflation. Um the geopolitical forces
behind gold are are uh are then later
discussed. Part of the reason why
investors flocked to gold post um 2022
was uh the weaponization of the dollar
and the loss of trust of US treasuries.
Prior to that, we had uh people rushing
to treasuries and the dollar for safety,
but loss of confidence brought them to
the yellow medal is one argument.
Anyway, can you just evaluate what I
said as well as what the um Goldman
Sachs an analyst uh projection has?
>> Yeah, I think gold is inherently
valuable because it has a long track
record of being perceived valuable by a
global population. This goes back to
your original question as to who finds
and determines value. And um gold
without a doubt has the longest proven
track record. When I got married, I was
gifted gold. When I had children, my
family gifted me gold. And all of these
constructs come from the notion that
these are hard assets that allow you to
opt out of having fiat economy. And
especially if you think that these
things can be um transportable then it's
actually even more interesting to think
about the kinds of flight risks in the
most tail edge of events where people
are trying to uh participate a
protection for. So I think in that sense
the psyche of gold is real. M
>> the geopolitical um contribution is also
real because after Breton Woods uh ended
in 1971,
>> it hasn't been that long for a whole
generation to still not remember the
role of gold. So there are people out
there who still remember the essence of
how you used to have capital that was
backed by assets that wasn't totally
dependent on just the trust
creditworthiness of the country. And so
that trend is important because if you
think about revisiting a world where we
return back to like a price specia
mechanism like a gold standard then gold
will come back and actually a lot of the
government institutions are buying gold
and the central banks are participating
because they're looking at gold as the
hedge for the day in which that will
contribute to collateralizing a new
world order. So to me this makes a lot
of sense.
>> Okay. Okay. And just the other side of
the equation, I'll pass it back to
Bonnie. He compared it to Bitcoin,
calling it a safer hedge than Bitcoin.
This is his quote regarding Bitcoin.
Bitcoin is more volatile and sensitive
to draw downs, more positively
correlated with tech equities. Bitcoin
and equities both do well when risk
sentiment is positive. So that partly
may contribute to the riskier aspect.
Can you evaluate what he just said
there?
>> Yeah. So, I think it's easy to dismiss
volatility as a feature that is a net
negative, but actually what I would
argue is young people actually embrace
volatility. Um, some of that I think is
a generational trend where they realize
that the opportunity cost is way too
high to not experience volatility to
achieve some level of wealth creation.
But the reality is volatility again is a
path dependent outcome where the only
thing investors really care about is the
terminal value. So if you really believe
Bitcoin is going to be valuable over a
long period of time, people can weather
the volatility. The thing that I worry a
little bit more as to where Bitcoin
falls a little short versus something
like gold is that most humans are not
very good at being um owners of their
own assets. Uh self-custodial ownership,
right? And it's actually perfectly human
to want to outsource that to somebody
else and say, "You manage the custody of
my assets because I'm afraid of those
risks." And Bitcoin turns that model
completely upside down. Right? Because
to truly own Bitcoin, you must do it in
a self-custodial way where you're
willing to entertain the possibility
that you'll lose it all if you mess up.
And most humans cannot tolerate that
risk. Gold has elements of this, but the
ability to lose all your gold is not
nearly as drastic in the ways that
people might just forget their keys.
Yeah.
>> Or actually have their keys stolen
because gold is still a material
physicality and that it exists in the
universe. And so when people um compare
gold and Bitcoin, I actually don't worry
about the volatility. I don't worry
about like the price. It's the
self-custodial aspect that I think many
people will still struggle with where
they're comforted by knowing they have a
physical object that they can hold,
smell, and taste and know that it is
here. Uh, and and Bitcoin feels at some
level a little bit abstract, which is
why some people still till this day
don't really believe it's materially
valuable.
>> But soon we can just leave our Bitcoin
with the banks.
Isn't that a lot easier? It removes the
concern. Yeah, I think this is the
innovation that we are embarking upon
which is how are we going to integrate
Bitcoin to a business model where we can
remove some of those tail risks of uh
loss and insurance but also not totally
lose the element of those being your
sovereign assets because the moment
these assets like Bitcoin become
contributed into a custody model where
you are no longer the owner, we're kind
of revisiting the uh the traditional
financial system as we have it and that
means that the exchange or the bank can
relend it and rehypothecate it and it
begins to kind of look a lot like what
we thought we were solving for. So I
think what we're really trying to figure
out is can we build a nicer user
experience that allows people to feel
comfort and safety in owning Bitcoin
where you get that white glove
experience but you are still the person
that own these assets in your name and I
think that is the great chapter that can
be unlocked with the growth that we see
in the industry. Are you seeing any
possible solution?
Are we close to any solution?
>> You know, I think the fact that the ETFs
have been very popular in uh its growth
trajectory shows you that there is a
version of owning price exposure without
worrying about that custody risk that is
valuable to investors. So I think in
some sense they can coexist. People
still want financialized version of
Bitcoin because that means it plays
nicely in their portfolio management
systems. They know how to margin it.
They can borrow against it. The borrow
market lets you lend your Bitcoin ETF
out without counterparty risks. Whereas
if you lend out your Bitcoin now there's
real counterparty risk. And so there's
certain features of the financial system
for which it can be very good. So I
think there will always be value for
needing a rapper that plays into the
traditional compliance system, but it
also doesn't mean it's mutually
exclusive that investors should not also
want to own some Bitcoin in cold custody
as well. And I think everyone should
actually do both because then you get to
really see why the experience has
different challenges but privileges that
are associated with it as well.
Going back to your Twitter post, you
talk about assets that transform time.
What does that even mean?
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, um, great question. I
consider time to be one of the component
of of of energy that can be created that
could in turn turn to value. So in many
ways I think Bitcoin represented a
concept of this through proof of work
where in able to actually mine a bitcoin
you actually have to expend a lot of
energy and time to get the block subsidy
which in turn is a battery almost that
has captured the effort uh and and has
given you a reward for it. That's why
the scarcity exists because time is
scarce and energy is scarce. I think
there's many other ways to apply this
which is there are human capital um in
itself that is scarce and actually the
use of that human capital can be
valuable. So the number one example I
point to people is professional
gambling. So when people think about
gambling I'm not talking about slot
machines right where like we're just you
know playing games that have negative
EVs. I'm talking about professional
gambling where real skills can add
positive EV outcomes. So poker is a
great example. Mhm.
>> If you're a great poker player, you can
generally have a positive EV outcome.
And that is because your time is
valuable cuz you're spending to it. And
the energy you have to expend to win is
not insignificant either. But that
income stream looks totally unrelated to
the stock market. It looks totally
unrelated to the interest rate policy.
It is just an ability to earn income
that is based on your human capital.
Another good example is sports betting.
Sports betting is widely known as one of
the most complex markets generally
because the information edge does favor
uh smart berstors. So there are
professional sports betterers who are
actually able to be better than the
bookies in which the bookies rely on the
best bettors to create the inside
market. So if you're a professional
sports better, that's another outcome of
an income stream that comes from
expending energy. And that kind of uh
ability to earn income I think should be
a component of how to imagine uh income
creation in your portfolio.
Well, in a recent report that Bidwise
asset management published, uh your
company is projecting significant
increases in ETF inflows into Bitcoin.
So I think by the order of 300 billion
anticipated by 2026, uh 120 billion by
the end of this year, up significantly
from uh what it was last year. So why
the significant growth over the next one
year?
>> Yeah, I think it goes back to the
comment you shared earlier in which the
risk of Bitcoin seems to be that it is
highly correlated to risk on assets and
I think what we are now seeing is that
those moments are also fleeting and we
are starting to see divergences of
Bitcoin's price action relative to
equities in ways that people are giving
it more optionality that it could
outperform in a risk on and risk off
environment. So I call this I call this
phenomenon um a positive row bitcoin or
a negative row bitcoin. Row is a Greek
in options terminology that implies a
change in value based on the change in
interest rate. And generally if you
thought interest rates were going to go
up that's a pretty challenging market
environment. It's a ch it's a it's a
market environment where people are
worried uh and in those situations that
are risk off you could imagine bitcoin
becomes a store of value. But
historically what happened was reverse
which is that Bitcoin is a risk on asset
right where rates go down Bitcoin is the
fastest horse because it fights
inflation the fastest. And the key is is
there a moment when Bitcoin can be both.
And I think what you're seeing is
through the volatile path if you zoom
out and look at the long history of
Bitcoin's price action it is actually
both positive row and negative row
depending on the market environment. And
I think that's why Bitcoin is valuable
and people are realizing there's now
over 10 years of track record of having
demonstrated this. And so the Bitcoin
ETF lets you access it in ways that
people can build their portfolio
thoughtfully. And financial adviserss
are finally understanding this use case
where it is no longer a scandalous
conversation to potentially suggest this
being important especially after US
credit ratings was downgraded most
recently and this ex issues with fiscal
expenditures is becoming a everyday
topic of conversation. I I I misspoke.
It wasn't just ETFs as the primary
source of inflow. It was $400 billion of
inflows into Bitcoin overall. But that
was actually my next question. break it
down for us uh percentage roughly of
that 400 billion being ETFs or spot or
futures or you know layer 2s whatever
the case may be
>> I think that the ETF market is going to
be relatively large at a global scale
and we have to remember we still don't
have ETFs in many markets yet for
example Korea does not have a a Bitcoin
ETF yet
>> and so those rappers are still growing
at a global scale and they are going to
become important because Like I said,
many humans do not want to actually deal
with the self-custodial risk of Bitcoin.
And I think that is a feature you have
to acknowledge that people find
valuable. And so that will be
complimentary to those who actually
still want to own Bitcoin directly
because they find that to be culturally
aligned with the mission. Um, but I
think what you'll see is most people are
economic investors and they want to earn
the best profit opportunities and having
it in the ETF rapper just lets you do
more things from a financialization
perspective, right? Think about the
popular basis trade where you go long
the spot Bitcoin asset and you go short
the Bitcoin futures and you're able to
collect that spread. those kinds of
trades become a little bit easier when
you're using um traditional assets that
allow cross margining with your prime
broker, a little bit more challenging to
do it with crypto assets today at least
uh on a capital efficiency basis. So I
think those kinds of reasons give you a
little bit of like a financial edge to
owning the ETF rapper for now than it
might be for the spot asset.
>> Earlier you talked about art or cards.
Um, is it easier to trade those things
if they're onchain? So, that means you
might be a believer of RWA.
Um, there are a lot of people out there
that don't believe it.
>> They're like, "We want our art on the
wall. We want to, you know, be able to
touch the gold." Um, break it down for
me.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I think RWA is a fascinating
trend and one where people apply
different versions of what they expect
that to capture. Um, for me there's two
emerging trends. One version of the RWA
is tokenization of existing financial
rappers that historically were illquid
but were bringing liquidity to those
financial assets. So think about private
equity, immensely illquid, private
credit, very liquid. But if you tokenize
it and maybe make the market a little
bit more tradable, you can imagine the
secondary market for what was
historically illquid does become more
liquid and tokenization permits that.
That's a version of an RWA story. The
other RWA is actually what about assets
that were never traded, never
securitized, has actually never been
created for trading purposes and can we
put them in a tokenized wrapper so they
find liquidity that's never found
before. That is the part that I find
more interesting which is to your
question things like trading cards or
sneakers these have great volume. People
trade these assets all the time.
Companies like StockX exist and make
great margins on the logistics of it.
But the logistics is actually a cost of
business because shipping sneakers and
storing them, paying insurance, all
those things are auxiliary cost to that
business model which ultimately the
consumers pay for.
>> The thing that onchain tokenization can
unlock for this is you could imagine a
whole new business where the certificate
of authenticity in itself being
represented by something that is digital
in nature would allow you to trade
ownership without the asset necessarily
moving. Uh, and so I think there's a lot
of companies that have tried this in the
past where the watch market, for
example, is very huge, very valuable,
and there's a lot of frauds. And so the
authenticity component is important, but
you also want to create like a trading
market where you don't have to move
around the watch every time. If the end
buyer doesn't want to claim it because
they're actually just interested in the
financial speculation, then you can see
RWA becomes more of a liquid market, but
you can almost then still imagine the
physical asset being claimable that it
gives it value. I'm just going to play
devil's advocate here. We've seen this
couple years ago when people started
making tokenized watches of Rolexes and
whatever.
>> Most of those went to zero. A Rolex is
still 25 grand.
>> Yeah.
>> So, we don't need it. That's my
argument.
>> In terms of the Rolex Rolexes
themselves,
>> no. in terms well that could be an
argument as well no in terms of the
digital Rolex we don't need to digitize
existing hard assets that's a
counterargument how would you respond to
that and the point I was trying to make
is that if you look at president
the digitized asset went to zero
>> right when whereas the real asset still
retained value
>> I think what you're intimating though is
the digital asset had no claim to a
physical asset right it was a metaverse
asset is what you're saying
>> it yeah it could have been or it could
have been or could have just been an NFT
right
>> of that particular asset.
>> Yeah. Yeah. A metaverse asset. Yeah. I'm
talking about a version where you
actually have a like a claim to the
physical asset.
>> Okay.
>> And the NFT permits the ease of trading
of that physical asset.
>> So that is a model that I think we have
also seen in crypto. Not many of them
have succeeded to date, but one that I
do think at the right inflection point
could be could be worthwhile.
>> Sure.
>> Yeah. I agree with you. Paying lots of
money for pictures. Did you remember
that time when people were like paying a
lot of money for digital stuff like
digital shoes and like digital Gucci's
and like people were buying digital
land?
I don't know what happened to the
digital land. Is that is that so big?
Yeah, you could just
>> create more land like there's no
scarcity. Anyway, we're going off topic.
>> Um all right, let's talk about uh
you as a trader. You were a derivatives
trader at Morgan Stanley. I just wonder
well first of all what exactly did you
trade and I'm just linking it back to
your current job and how you apply those
lessons.
>> Yeah I uh I I started my career trading
exotic options
>> in equity derivatives at Morgan Stanley.
What that means is there are a whole
class of financial instruments that are
so complex that black shores is not good
enough to price those assets.
>> Wow. Because black shores has actually a
pretty deterministic model and what you
actually need for some exotic options is
a stochastic model that is actually pat
dependent and taking a lot of different
local volatility inputs. So these things
are hybrid options, barrier options,
knock-ins, knockouts. You may not have
heard of any of these, but these are
essentially some of the most complex
financial engineering for a variety of
insurance or speculation purposes. And
so the thing that is most worrisome for
exotics traders like myself in these
moments is you're always worried that
the model can't capture perfectly the
most extreme events because the most
extreme events are very challenging to
model correctly even with stoastic
volatility where the correlation between
some inputs cannot be captured
correctly. So for example if spot goes
up
>> generally that has an implication for
what volatility will do. the spot goes
down. We know volatility tends to go up,
>> but you need to be able to incorporate
some correlation in that path dependency
in these models that can be sometimes
very unstable.
>> And so part of the reason why I think I
discovered Bitcoin and its interest
really early on was because I was
basically pricing events that no one
thinks could happen. for example.
>> So, so tail options, everything about
exotic options is imagining the most
adverse scenario of something that you
otherwise wouldn't think would be
probably priced.
>> And so, you have to assume these tail
events that are, you know, three
standard deviations might be more
probable than you think. And so, when I
discovered Bitcoin, it was that moment
when most people will be skeptical and
say, "Hey, this looks funny. It seems
like it's interesting, but it's probably
worthless and it's probably going to go
to zero." I think I was naturally wired
to imagine, well, what if it doesn't go
to zero? If it doesn't go to zero, it's
actually probably worth a lot. And that
probability calculation can be very
challenging for most humans where the
outcome is zero or extremely valuable,
but the percentage of that happening is
low.
>> When did you get started with Bitcoin
again?
>> So, I learned about it in 2010 on the
trading floor and I purchased my first
uh three years thereafter.
>> Okay. So, 2013. If you had taken the
let's take the price chart of Bitcoin up
until 2013 and plug that into one of
your models, would Bitcoin reaching 100K
back in 2013, would that have been a
three standard deviation event?
>> Oh man, that would have been like a 15
standard event. Yeah.
>> Yet it made it. How?
>> Lots of time and energy and focus.
No, I mean the reality is we're still on
this journey and we don't know still
what the price of Bitcoin's ceiling
ultimately is. But I also tell folks
when you bet on Bitcoin, you're not
always betting on the price of Bitcoin
going up. Sometimes you're betting on
the price of fiat going down. And that's
another mentality that I think is
something counterintuitive to imagine,
but most of Bitcoin's value creation
really happened because fiat got
debased. And that's what was, I think,
happening at a faster pace than people
imagined ever since the global financial
crisis.
>> With Bitcoin, I think most people
understand. Can I replace Bitcoin with
altcoins?
Does that model still work?
>> I think my personal opinion is that
right now we're living in a Bitcoin or
bust world. Everyone really likes
Bitcoin and all coins are suffering at
some level finding some conviction. But
I think with clarity in market structure
and utilities around these things
existing for financial purposes that are
more than just mimemetic trading could
imagine that altcoins could be useful. I
think for now the experience so far has
been most people bought altcoins because
they really like the levered volatility
to crypto. So you know if Bitcoin is
going up 5% you thought the altcoin
might go up 15%. So you're going to buy
the altcoin. And what you've seen the
last 9 months really and maybe even
longer now is that correlation has
completely broken apart. Bitcoin can go
up and all coins can go down. It's
actually no longer a lever bet on
Bitcoin. I think part of why that also
is the case is when the ETF was
approved, you actually got the chance to
now trade options on those Bitcoin ETFs
in December of last year. So actually,
if you want levered Bitcoin exposure,
you can just trade call options on
Bitcoin instead. Is that why the altcoin
market is less active now than before?
I'm just speculating here because if I
wanted to be a DGEN instead of buying
some memecoin, I could just buy options
on Bitcoin. That g me the same kind of
high.
>> Exactly. You get the same kind of
experience, the thrill of the ups and
downs with levered exposure and it's
safer because the basis risk is gone.
You don't have to worry about the
Bitcoin and Helium relationship or the
Bitcoin Salana relationship.
>> And so Bitcoin options make a ton of
sense. And the second thing that
happened is these Bitcoin treasury
companies came along, right? The micro
strategies of the world, those are also
more volatile than Bitcoin. And so I
consider both Bitcoin options and the
rise of these treasury companies like
the Micro Strategies, the Met Planets
are all taking volume away from altcoin
trading where retail investors are
choosing to just bet differently on the
degenerate kind of betting as you would
describe it where these companies, these
securities are saving that interest with
a little bit cleaner basis risk to the
actual exposure you want, which is
Bitcoin.
you know, there are other um companies
trying to copy strategy strategy with
Salana or with Ethereum. Um, do you
think it works?
>> I'm really excited to see if it will
work. I I'm optimistic that it can find
some product market fit and I'll tell
you why. I think Bitcoin has worked so
far because everyone believes Bitcoin is
valuable, right? So, you can borrow
against it and people are willing to
give it some creditworthiness. So
strategy is able to tap into the credit
market because having certain amount of
bitcoins gives those lenders an
appreciation to think that there's value
for them to recover. So the first thing
is you must believe these asset
collateral is valuable and bitcoin
succeeds in this in every dimension. You
might argue this doesn't succeed with
any other asset today in crypto such as
Ethereum or Salana. Some will disagree
and some will otherwise agree. That's an
open question. I'm excited to see how
people underwrite. But I'll tell you why
these treasury strategies work in
addition to the credit collateral. One
is it works if the underlying asset is
volatile because the leverage on
volatility is what is creating value for
these corporate treasuries and Ethereum
and Salana happen to be both more
volatile than Bitcoin. So that's plus
one for ETH, plus one for Salana. That's
advantageous. The other thing is Bitcoin
is today at least a fairly dormant
passive asset. Like it exists and people
kind of let it be. You don't really earn
income off. You don't stake it. You
know, it lives in cold custody. You put
it under your mattress. It looks like
gold. But Ethereum is not, right?
Everyone knows in Ethereum you actually
kind of have to participate in the
network security to earn the incremental
yield that is provided by proof uh proof
of stake where restaking has emerged as
a theme and there's other things that
you can do with ETH that gives you
incremental yield than actually just
keep it in cold custody
>> and ETFs don't actually do that just yet
but these operating companies might be
able to do that. So the benefit here I'm
alluding to is that the asset could be
maybe even a little bit more productive
in an operating company structure in a
way that Bitcoin doesn't have to be and
then you add the volatility on top and
those things can be potentially edges
for those proof ofstake tokens that
proof of work tokens don't compete with.
Any lessons you've learned from Morgan
Stanley's experience that you're
applying to your trading experiences
today?
>> Um man, I learned a lot of lessons at
Morgan Stanley. Uh I'm trying to think
if any of them were super relevant to
crypto. Um
you know the number one lesson uh I I
was told um was uh don't f up. And rule
number two is there is no rule number
two only rule number one. Uh and I think
in crypto it's very easy to participate
in some of the more speculative things
that are out there and look pretty
experimental. Uh, and I think I try to
be a little bit more conservative in
being able to access some of those new
opportunities where we do have lots of
exogenous risk factors there in even
brands of protocols that you would think
were fairly blue chip. And so I always
have this kind of devil in the back of
my head sharing those rules from Morgan
Stanley that makes me wait just a little
bit more before I click some buttons.
Um, and that's why I think maybe at some
point I'm a Bitcoin maxi too. So, you
have gone through the period of time
where you bought altcoins.
>> Of course, of course. I've done them
all. Um I And and it's funny because uh
you know, you do these things and you
realize these codes are living breathing
things. And sometimes these protocols
upgrade and they change and they go
through new tokconomics and you're
supposed to have swapped something for
another and if you didn't, it's gone.
Yeah.
>> And you actually have to pay attention.
And there is no ISS proxy service for
crypto assets where they'll mail you and
they say, "Hey, by this deadline, you
have to elect to do this." And nobody
tells you. And so,
>> or they just post on Twitter,
>> they post on Twitter because they can't
reach you. And so, I find that very
interesting. Um, it's one of the use
cases as to why crypto adoption has been
so challenging for most investors. Um,
and it's funny too when you forget you
were staking something for two years and
you discover it and you're like, "Oh,
yeah. I forgot about that." uh and there
are these big projects that come and go
throughout the years.
>> What's your message to retail investors
watching right now who think they can
trade options and are interested in
getting into that market and that kind
of game. What would you tell a beginner
who's interested?
>> I would tell every beginner that it is a
critical skill at this point in your
life to learn how to trade options. Um
and I say this because options trading
is incredibly useful as a mental model
to think about the world through a
probabilistic lens. And I think more and
more, not even from economics, but the
culture has changed where everyone wants
things to be black and white. You're
either, you know, hard yes, hard no,
hard right, hard left, and there's no
room for nuance. But the reality is the
world is full of nuances. And so options
trading trains your brain to be a little
bit more mindful about the distribution
of outcomes that might be possible. So
then on top of that, add to the reality
that most of the trading in the world is
fairly um alpha rich for those who know
what they're doing. And so you're always
going to be at a little bit of a
disadvantage unless you're able to get
up to speed on the things that matter.
And options trading gives you a lot of
leverage that only retail investors can
actually benefit from the most. In my
opinion,
options trading represents the one thing
that retail traders can do better than
institutions because when institutions
trade options, they need size. And when
they are size, they move markets. But if
you're a retail participant and you're
just buying a few lots here and there,
you're not moving the price. And you're
actually not showing open interest to
other people in ways people can then
trade around your positions. M
>> so I've been telling folks for a long
time retail investors it's very hard to
out compete institutions it's almost
stacked against you don't know the order
flow you don't know what the central
limit book looks like you're just
trading options is the one thing where
size is in your advantage as a real
participant so everyone should take the
time to learn it and also bitcoin is one
of the most leptoctoic assets in the
world and so if you believe in bitcoin I
think optionalized bitcoin is actually a
really worthwhile endeavor for someone
who has a long time span to observe it.
>> I feel like that was a perfect ending.
>> I have one more question today.
>> Okay,
>> let's see if we can make this more
perfect.
>> Okay,
>> I don't know if I can, but let me try. A
>> lot of pressure here.
>> Yeah, a lot of pressure.
>> You said that when you got married, you
got you were gifted gold.
>> Oh,
>> when your kids get married, what are you
giving them?
>> Oh, man. I will have to honor my family
and pass down my gold as well,
>> but I would absolutely love to include
Bitcoin in this conversation. It's funny
you say that because my son actually um
you know being around me now he's 5
years old has picked up some of the
conversations that my wife and I happen
to have and we do talk about Bitcoin
sometimes over a dinner table and every
now and then he'll ask daddy like what's
the price of Bitcoin? But he hasn't
gotten to the point where he understands
like big numbers. So he doesn't know a
100,000 or 90,000. It's 100 or 90.
>> So he'll go around.
>> You have to explain to him in terms of
Pokémon cards. Like this is how many
Pokémon cards can buy.
>> I do Pokemon.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, it's true.
>> You don't do Pokemon. Everybody else
does. You're not cool, Bonnie.
>> I actually had the perfect story to tell
you now. My son has been trading Pokemon
cards with his friends
>> and he has basically traded away some of
the legitimate cards that he received
for what are these fake cards that you
can buy on Amazon
>> and Amazon the cards are fake. It's made
in China but they're very pretty. So
they're like gold and it glitters and
you can almost see that card looks like
it's more valuable. So my son traded
away all his legitimate original cards
to get these gold cards. And he was so
proud to show me, "Daddy, look at these
gold cards."
>> And I didn't want to tell him they're
fake.
>> And so I had to leverage Bitcoin in this
conversation where I was trying to
explain to him that the blue cards are
the original and they're scarce
>> like Bitcoin.
>> It's pristine collateral.
>> And he knows what pristine collateral
means because it's how I've described
Bitcoin in the past. Mh.
>> So now he goes, "Oh, so this is pristine
collateral. I'm not trading it away."
>> Wow. All right. Good education. Good
education for the audience as well.
Thank you very much, Chef. That was very
educational.
>> Thanks for having me. Super fun.
>> Thank you. Thank you.